# **Kadir Lofca**

## Software & Game Development

(336) 802-0127 <u>Jinkedin.com/in/kadirlofca</u> <u>Jgithub.com/kadirlofca</u>

I'm an enthusiastic computer science student with experience as a software developer and undergraduate researcher. I have been featured in the <u>UNCG Science Magazine</u> for my work in VR. I write clean code, communicate well, and am excited to build great things!

#### **SKILLS**

- C#, C++, Python
- Unity, Unreal Engine, Visual Studio, Blender, Audacity, Photoshop
- GitHub, GitLab, Slack, Asana, Microsoft Teams

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of North Carolina Greensboro – Expected May 2024

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.

#### **Guilford Technical Community College – October 2019 to May 2020**

• Successfully finished AP/university level courses during high school.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Virtual Reality <u>Time Perception Research</u> – August 2021 to Present

Undergraduate Researcher

- Designed VR experience aimed at studying human time perception by researching past studies and discussing with mentor.
- Used Blender to model exact replica of laboratory where experiment was conducted.
- Utilized SteamVR to simultaneously track the positions of 4 objects and display them in VR.
- Programmed reusable tool to automatically create and export data tables from Unity.
- Analyzed 480 data points by utilizing R and RStudio.
- Secured progress of project by pushing versions to GitLab.

### Magnolia House Virtual Reality Tour - February 2021 to August 2021

Software Engineering (VR) Intern

- Led team from development to successful launch of VR tour.
- Programmed VR teleportation and menu controls using C# and Unity.
- Created realistic shaders and materials using Unity's shader graph tool.
- Increased frame rate by 50% using frustum and occlusion culling in Unity, and reducing poly-count in Blender.
- Simulated realistic audio with a low-pass filter based on listener's position.
- Utilized GitHub to manage versions of project.

#### Hackathon HackReality 2021 – March 2021

Programmer, Team Lead (Team of 4)

- Programmed system to hold and drop physics objects in VR using C++ and vector math.
- Created VR game avatar capable of teleporting using Blueprints.
- Led team of 4 to successfully create <u>VR puzzle game</u> using Unreal Engine 4.

## Game Development Tool Quick Character - October 2022

Programmer

- Recreated popular games' character movement systems using C# and Unity.
- Programmed a scalable state machine for character movement states such as walking, falling, wall running.
- Wrote clean, extensive documentation for game development tool.

## Game Jam <u>GMTK 2022</u> - July 2022

Programmer, Artist

- Led team through design and development stages of an action game.
- Implemented health and combat system for game characters using C# and Unity.
- Created character art, voiced a character, and designed a level.

### Workshop <u>HackNC 2022</u> – May 2022 to November 2022

Programmer, Workshop Instructor

- Led workshop about game development for hackathon attendees.
- Demonstrated game development and programming fundamentals by creating a 2D game with Godot and visual scripting.

#### **ACTIVITIES, SERVICE & OTHER**

#### **Epic Games' Unreal Engine Accelerator Experience – October 2022**

Unreal Engine Technical Support Volunteer

• Assisted over 20 concurrent attendees in navigating and troubleshooting Unreal Engine 5.

## Interactive Realities Lab – February 2021 to Present

Member & Study Logistics Czar

• Managed laboratory schedule for 10+ members by appointing study and research dates.

## **Association for Computing Machinery University Chapter – May 2020 to Present**

Member & Treasurer

• Managed club finances and organized weekly club meetings for up to 30 attendees by inviting speakers and preparing technology related presentations.

## Unreal Engine Related YouTube Channel - April 2020 to Present

Video Editor, Channel Manager

- Reached 50,000+ views by producing game design and development videos.
- Recorded and edited 30+ videos using DaVinci Resolve and Audacity.

#### **Barry Goldwater Scholarship – October 2021**

Nominee

• Nominated for prestigious scholarship by University of North Carolina Greensboro based on exceptional research and academic success.

#### Convocation Day for the College of Arts & Science - August 2021

Panel Speaker

 Shared academic success insights to incoming freshmen upon invitation from University of North Carolina Greensboro.